Paul Dilley

EXPERIENCE

Ticko Inc, Toronto — Senior Software Developer

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

React Native mobile app:

- Built a mobile app that processed object detection data and overlaid it onto video, whilst managing the slow nature of React Native, to ensure the video and overlay were synchronized correctly.
- Researched and tested React Navigation, React Native Reanimated and push notifications.

Flutter mobile app:

• Created a mobile app to show a video feed and allow opening/closing of doors, and used a system of reusable widgets.

Instacart Inc, Toronto — *Software Engineer*

NOVEMBER 2018 - AUGUST 2021

As part of the Cart, Checkout & Payments team:

- As a key member of an agile team, I developed the frontend for the Checkout, Order and Payment customer flows, having completed important tasks, such as:
 - Upgraded the relevant flows from Angular JS to React JS, and added a new "Leave order at door" section in a timely manner to adapt to the pandemic.
 - Maintained and bug fixed the Cordova mobile wrapper for the checkout components.
 - Built new Order screen components using React JS, with Emotion (CSS), to show order status live-updates.
- Integrated various payment components for our clients, into the checkout and order screens (BrainTree V3, FirstData V2, WegPay, Stripe).
- Ensured the frontend payment components were PCI compliant and added Recaptcha to the payment flows.
- Made backend additions to support frontend requirements (Python).

JinnTech & Vapeshot Inc, Toronto — Freelancer

APRIL 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

ZeroProjects Inc:

• Developed the frontend for an employee management system to help JinnTech catalog developers and designers for software projects contracted to the company (ReactJS, Redux).

Vapeshot Inc:

 Created a responsive webpage for their vape product, and ensured the page displayed desirably and functionally from large desktop screens to small mobile devices (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery).

CONTACT

301–1500 Eglinton Ave W, Toronto, M6E 2G5 **647-228-5876 pldilley@gmail.com** http://dilley.ca

PROFILE

Senior developer of 10 years with a focus on frontend development using ReactJS and AngularJS, experience with React Native and Flutter, and in Java and Python. Motivated self-starter accustomed to working in fast-paced, agile environments within cross-functional teams.

SKILLS

Frontend: Javascript (ES6+), ReactJS (JSX and Redux), AngularJS, ExtJS, HighCharts.

Mobile: Cordova, React Native, Flutter (Dart).

Backend: Java, Python, NodeJS, SQL.

Web: Tomcat, JSP, Spring Framework, Jersey, HTML, CSS / SASS, JSON, Browser extensions.

Build Tools: Npm, Webpack, Expo, Maven, Gulp.

Dev Tools: Git (Github), Atlassian (Jira, Stash), browser developer tools, Intellij IDE, VSCode.

Ticko Inc, Toronto — Senior Software Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - APRIL 2018

Development of investment research tools for an investor platform:

- Created a live-tracking investment reporting platform similar to Questrade (Ext JS 6.5, HighCharts).
- Created a Chrome/Firefox browser extension that is capable of webpage highlighting and annotation for research.

Development of a Cordova mobile app to manage a door access system:

- Created a mobile website that showed live camera feed and opening/closing of doors (React JS, EXT JS 6).
- Adapted it to a Progressive Web App: Browser push notifications and service worker caching for faster loading.
- Converted the website to work as a mobile app that can be installed (Apache Cordova).

Centro Inc (formerly Sitecout), Toronto — *Software Developer*

SEPTEMBER 2011 - NOVEMBER 2016

Supported the original RTB ad tech platform and acted as team lead for the creation of the next product iteration:

- At the company start-up stage: Quickly built new features to meet customer demands and help the company expand rapidly.
- Worked effectively in a team to deliver an upgrade to the entire product with additional features within a strict six-month deadline (Ext JS 4 javascript framework, SASS css framework).
- Implemented a custom Maven plugin to fully automate the UI build process (Java).
- Refactored a middleware layer to work with the company's new API (Spring Framework / Java).
- Worked in a fast-paced agile scrum team, with focus on web app performance optimization.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Asynchronous Javascript Framework

Creating my own Javascript Framework similar to ReactJS that uses Javascript features alone (e.g. template literals), renders completely asynchronously and keeps all state in one place.

Health App using React Native

Building a health app to help with weight loss.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours), Software Engineering University of Sheffield, UK (2007-2010)

City & Guilds: Level 3 Advanced, Java Software Development North Herts College, UK (2007)